It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
어지러운 전국 시대.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
Musashi is here-dasu!
무사시 등장이오!
Karakuri Kengouden
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
A man always dreams of the day
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
in the center of the world to become
제일 강해질 날을
AH! AH! the strongest
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
모험의 길의 막을 연다
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
Go! Fight!
가라! 싸워라!
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
Tomorrow will be glorious
내일은 빛난다
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Fight the utmost with the stillness
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
His eyes shined! Musashi!
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
During their trip, Musashi and others reunited with Baiken once again.
여행 도중 무사시 일행은 바이켄과 재회했다.
And Baiken offered hospitality in a superb mansion.
그리고 바이켄은 훌륭한 저택에서 요리를 대접해 주었다.
But their happiness didn't last long; they had to fight against a monster named Nue.
그러나 기쁨도 잠시, 괴물 누에하고 싸우는 처지가 되었다.
But thanks to the friendly aid from Baiken and cooperation from Kojirō,
하지만 바이켄의 우정의 조력과 코지로의 협력으로 오니히메가 조종하는 누에를 쓰러뜨리고 다테 가를 구했다.
Shuten Explodes
슈텐, 대폭발이오
What's going on at the Cursed Valley deep here?
이 깊숙한 곳의 저주의 골짜기. 대체 뭔 일인가.
What could that be?
뭔가, 저건...
Gohachi and Heisuke that I thought to be lost are also there!
게다가 행방불명된 고하치도 헤이스케도 있군.
I must let villagers know about this.
마을 사람들에게 알려야...
Are you sure that we aren't lost?
역시 길을 잘못 든 게.
My nose is working fine-dasu!
내 코에 문제는 없소!
You have zero scientific evidences.
과학적 근거는 제로구나.
That's not it-dasu.
그런 것 아니오.
Don't fight over something that pointless! Let's just hurry up to an inn in a lively town.
둘 다 쓸데없는 걸로 싸우지 마! 빨리 번화가에 있는 역참이나 가자.
We're not going to find one at this rate.
여기서는 어떻게 해도 못 찾을 거야.
Huh?
어?
This! My nose definitely works perfectly-dasu! Tasty-looking manjus-dasu!
이거! 내 코는 역시 잘 듣소! 맛있어 보이는 만주이오!
Hey, Musashi!
어이! 무사시!
Musashi!
무사시!
Who is it?!
누구냐?!
You, karakuri martial artist! Have a match with me!
카라쿠리 무예가! 나하고 승부다!
A match?
승부?
Forget it, kiddo.
관둬라, 얘야.
I am not a kiddo! I am Santa! Face me!
얘 아니야! 나, 산타야! 승부해!
You coward! That's unforgivable, even for a child-dasu!
이런 비겁한 놈! 얘라고 해도 용서 못 하오!
It's because you touched the offering to Ksitigarbha!
지장보살의 공물에 손을 댔기 때문이다!
W- what-dasu?!
뭐, 뭣이오?!
Stop right there, Musashi.
거기까지, 무사시.
Santa is right! You were being greedy.
산타가 말하는 대로! 천한 짓을 하니까 그러지!
But Kojirō don't give me any allowances or buy me snacks...
그래도 코지로가 용돈도 안 주고 간식도 안 사 주니까...
Why did you give a surprise attack?
왜 기습했나.
I just tested your skills.
조금 실력을 시험해 봤어.
Test?
시험?
I see! You want to be a martial artist, right?
알겠어! 너도 무예가가 되고 싶은 거구나?
I will become a parent like my dad!
난 당연히 아빠같은 부모님이 될 거야!
Care to elaborate?
사정이 있는 것 같구나.
While you look like you're showing off, you seem to be pretty capable. You're hired.
폼내는 것 같긴 해도 조금은 할 줄 아는 것 같네. 널 고용할게.
Hire me?
날 고용해?
It's not for free, of course. Take my treasure.
물론 공짜는 아니고, 내 보물이야.
This is gold dust!
이건 사금!
-So, is it gold-dasu? -Those are large drops!
-그러니까 금이오? -어라, 꽤 굵구나.
Will you accept this?
받아 줄거야?
But, you know...
음, 그래도...
I will take that instead-dasu!
내가 받아 주겠소!
No way you're rescuing my dad!
너라면 아빠 못 구해!
Tch, he's not cute at all-dasu...
칫, 귀엽지 않소...
-Kojirō? -I can't let this pass by.
-코지로? -가만히 두고만 볼 수는 없네요.
With that much gold, all that manjus, dangos, sweet red bean paste, and...
저만큼의 금이 있다면, 만주에 단고에 양갱에...
That's going to get me a meal of lifetime-dasu!
배가 가득히 차도록 먹겠소!
Hey, wait for me! I'm going too-dasu!
아, 기다리시오! 나도 가오!
What is it, Jiraiyan?
지라이얀, 뭐냐.
Shuten wanted to pay for his failures.
슈텐이 반성의 의미로 드리겠다며...
Gold bars, eh... But this is not enough for redemption of failure of getting Senhime.
금괴인가... 그러나 이 정도만 올려봤자는 센히메 습격에 실패한 것만큼은 못 된다.
We know that well. Not only this, but also we wanted to offer you war funds of thousands and millions of ryos instead.
잘 알고 있습니다. 이것보다도 몇만, 몇백 만 양의 군자금을 대신 바치고 싶다고...
Now that's a different story. A huge sum of war funds is required to take General Ieyasu down and become the shōgun.
그렇다면 이야기가 다르다. 제너럴 이에야스를 쓰러뜨리고 쇼군이 되기 위한 막대한 군자금가 있으니 말이지.
Yessir. I'll be back after making war funds with Shuten.
예. 슈텐과 함께 군자금을 만들어 오겠습니다.
Then.
그럼.
Wait, Jiraiyan.
기다려라, 지라이얀.
Leave the gold mountain to Shuten. You will keep an eye on Jūbee.
금산은 슈텐에게 맡겨라. 너는 주베를 쫓아라.
Jūbee?
주베를?
That rat Jūbee...
주베 놈...
It is clear that he is protecting Senhime and others in shadow and observing us in the back.
센히메 일행을 그림자 속에서 지키며 뒤에서 우리 행동을 감시하고 있는 게 명백하다.
That's why I'm ordering you, Jiraiyan, to find out Jūbee's traces and assassinate him.
그러니까, 지라이얀, 너는 주베의 행방을 밝혀내어 암살해라.
Yessir.
예.
And when we take Senhime into our hands, we'll take the shōgunate down at once.
그리고 센히메를 억누를 때, 단숨에 막부를 쓰러뜨리겠다.
And then, the world will fall into my hands.
그 이후에는 이 한조의 천하가 되는 것이다.
Missing?
행방불명?
Yeah. They went to hunt or pick mushrooms. 8 people from our village are missing, too.
응, 사냥하러 간 사람이나 버섯 따러 간 사람이라던가... 우리 마을에도 8명이야.
And your dad...
그리고 아버지도...
In The Cursed Valley, there must be an evil creature.
이 저주의 골짜기에 마물이 있는 게 틀림없어.
Yeah.
응.
Hm? My nose is detecting something-dasu.
음? 내 코가 무언가를 느끼오.
That fish is dead-dasu.
물고기가 죽어 있소.
What's going on-dasu?
어떻게 된 일이오?
The water must be toxic.
분명 이 물은 독일 거야.
A evil creature must be taking place.
역시 마물이 자리잡은 거야.
There's nothing to worry about evil creatures-dasu! I'll cut it with my dual blades-dasu!
뭐가 마물이오! 이 무사시가 이도류로 팍팍 썰어 주겠소!
And...
그리고...
It was from the creature.
마물의 소리야.
That's the sound of the creature-dasu.
저것이 마물의 소리이오.
Leave it to me-dasu!
내게 맡기시오!
Must be Senhime and Musashi.
저건 센히메와 무사시 일행.
O- Orochi!
오, 오로치!
Secret sword! Tsubamegaeshi!
비검! 츠바메가에시!
I will never forget the failure and the humiliation I received from them even if I die.
그 때의 실패, 녀석들에게 받은 굴욕은 죽어도 잊지 않겠다.
Your eternal grave will take place in the Cursed Valley.
저주의 골목이 너희들의 영원한 무덤이 될 지어다.
You will see.
두고 보자.
T- this is...
이, 이건...
Daddy!
아빠!
Do not come, Santa!
산타, 오지 마라!
Santa!
산타!
You cursed monster!
네 이놈, 괴물 놈!
You really did it!
했겠소!
My body is getting stiff-dasu!
으악! 몸이 뻣뻣해지오!
Santa!
산타!
Dad!
아빠!
Musashi! Santa!
무사시! 산타!
Senhime, please hide somewhere safe.
센히메 님, 숨어 계세요.
Secret sword! Tsubamegaeshi!
비검! 츠바메가에시!
Are you alright?
괜찮나?
Damn you!
네 이놈!
Kojirō!
코지로!
You...!
너는...
One of Four Rulers of Iga, Shutentiger!
이하 사천왕의 하나. 슈텐타이거!
You will face my wrath today!
오늘로써 원한을 풀어 주겠다!
Kojirō and Musashi shall be cooked in due time.
코지로에 무사시, 천천히 요리해 주겠다.
Not only my dad but also everyone... What should I do?
아빠뿐만이 아니라 모두 다... 이걸 어째...
What a terrible crisis! Wait for the stormy latter half!
자, 절체절명의 대위기! 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
I will dispatch you as an offering along with these treasures. Behave until then.
이 보물과 함께 공물로 함께 보내 주겠다. 그 때까지 얌전히 있어라.
Musashi... Kojirō...
무사시... 코지로...
You bastards! Work properly!
이 놈들아! 똑바로 일해라!
Do you want to end up like this?
이런 꼴이 되고 싶나?
Hurry up and work!
빨랑빨랑 일해라!
Now, how should I cook them up?
자, 저 녀석들을 어떻게 요리해 줄까.
Dad...
아빠...
Santa...
산타...
Hey, dad!
아, 아빠!
I see! Water washes mud away!
그렇구나. 진흙이니까 물에 약하지!
Santa!
산타!
Dad!
아빠!
Plucking your head off won't be enough for my grudge.
한방에 모가지를 날리는 것으로는 원한이 안 풀리지.
I will kill you with this, little by little.
이걸로 조금씩 조금씩 죽여 주겠어.
How does that feel?!
어떠냐, 기분은?
I see, I see! You're happy!
그렇군, 그렇군! 기쁘구나!
Stop it-dasu!
그만두시오!
It's almost there, Musashi! My chainsaw will tear off your body into pieces.
이제 곧이다, 무사시! 슬슬 체인소가 네 몸을 찢어갈길 거야.
It seems that it's touching your body. Time to break you into two pieces.
오, 닿은 것 같구나. 지금 두 동강내 주겠다.
Take this!
이랴!
You! What was that for?!
너희들! 뭔 짓이냐!
Unforgivable!
용서할 수 없다!
Santa!
산타!
Die!
죽어라!
Stop-dasu!
스톱이오!
I'll face you-dasu!
내가 상대해 주겠소!
What an impudent brat! I'll face you as you wished!
건방진 꼬맹이군! 원하는 대로 상대해 주겠다!
Santa, please take care of Kojirō of Osenchan-dasu!
산타, 코지로하고 오센짱을 부탁하오!
Leave it to me!
맡겨 둬!
You're better than I thought, Musashi!
그래도 다시 봤어, 무사시!
Dual blades? How presumptuous of you!
에이, 주제넘게 이도류 따위를 쓰다니!
Avira hum kham, Mohenjo-Daro!
아비라훔캄, 모헨조다로!
(lit. Mound of the Dead; an archaeological city in Indus Valley Civilization)
(인더스 문명의 도시 유적으로 "죽음의 언덕"이란 의미를 가지고 있음)
You're here again-dasu! That monster before!
또 나왔소! 아까 그 괴물!
Oh, that's not gonna work anymore-dasu!
저런, 그 수는 다시는 안 먹히오!
That's cheating-dasu!
교활하오!
I look miserable again-dasu!
또 꼴불견이오!
My eyes are spinning-dasu~
눈이 팽팽 도오~
Cut it off-dasu!
적당히 좀 하시오!
Musashi! That clay warrior is made out of mud!
무사시! 그 흙인형 진흙으로 되어 있어!
Use water to wash off mud!
진흙은 물에 약해!
I got it-dasu!
알았소!
Chase me if you can, you pile of mud-dasu! How's this?!
여기까지 쫒차 보시오, 진흙더미! 어떤지!
I did it-dasu!
해냈소!
Shuten! Take my Tsubamegaeshi!
슈텐! 츠바메가에시를 받아보아라!
Secret sword or not, that Tsubamegaeshi won't work twice!
아무리 비검 츠바메가에시라 해도, 두번은 안 통한다!
Avira hum kham, rock smasher!
아비라훔캄, 바위 으깨기!
You really did it-dasu!
잘도 했겠소!
Using sorcery like that is cowardly-dasu! Face me with your sword like a real man-dasu!
그런 요술, 비겁하오! 검으로 사내답게 승부보시오!
Don't make me laugh! Victory is what matters. Just win.
웃기지 마라! 이기면 된다. 이기면.
W- who was that?!
누, 누구냐?
That brat!
에잇, 이 꼬맹이!
Now-dasu!
지금이오!
What?!
뭐야?!
I can't take my sword back!
칼이 빠지지 않아!
Niten'ichiryū! Kanibasami no Tachi-dasu!
이천일류, 가위치기 칼이오!
That was close.
위험했다.
Showing off again? I could have dodged that myself-dasu!
또 멋진 척하기는. 혼자서라도 충분히 피했소!
I gotta show off for at least once.
나도 한 번은 잘난 꼴 보여줘야지.
You bastard! Avira hum kham, hurricane form!
네이놈! 아비라훔캄, 허리케인 정태!
Go! We're rescuing Kojirō and Musashi!
자, 코지로 씨하고 무사시 씨를 구해라!
Push!
이랴!
-The tornado -has stopped!
-회오리가 -멈췄어!
Secret sword! Tsubamegaeshi!
비검! 츠바메가에시!
Prepare yourself, Shuten!
슈텐, 각오!
Niten'ichiryū! Jūmonjigiri!
이천일류, 열십자 가르기!
Wow, it's pretty!
와, 예쁘다!
Whoa...
이야...
Ack, it's gold-dasu, it's gold-dasu! That's such a waste-dasu!
으악, 금이오, 금이오! 아깝소!
Curse those rats... Musashi's group again...
네 이놈... 또 무사시 일행이 방해를...
Unforgivable! I will take their lives away, whatever it takes!
용서할 수 없다! 어떤 수를 써서라도 반드시 목숨을 끊어 주겠다.
We are sincerely grateful for all your work here.
정말 어떤 보답을 해야 할지...
Thank you, Kojirō and Osenchan.
고마워. 코지로 씨. 오센짱.
Your father surely understands what you have felt by now, Santa!
으응, 아버지도 이제 산타의 기분을 알아주셨을 거야.
-Hey, where's Musashi? -Huh?
-어라, 무사시는? -어?
All that gold we could have gotten-dasu...
저 만큼의 금이 팍 흩어졌소.
I'm going to recover my investment by stuffing rice-dasu.
그런대로 밥이라도 먹어서 본전을 찾겠소.
Hey, Musashi! Stop being so gluttonous!
어이, 무사시! 주접스런 짓 하지 마라!
One more bite...
으악, 한 입만 더...
What a gourmand he is.
정말 먹보라니까.
You're right. He should be practicing self-discipline, and moreover, this is a trip with an important objective.
맞는 말입니다. 수행하는 주제에, 게다가 큰 목적이 있는 여행인데도.
I'm hungry... Dango... Manju...
배고프오... 단고... 만주...
-Musashi! -Huh?
-무사시 씨! -어?
Santa!
산타!
Is anything wrong-dasu?
뭔 일 있소?
Here! Your lunch box.
이거! 도시락이야.
Yes! Santa's parents are great!
우와! 역시 산타네 부모님이오!
You can't train when you're hungry. Give it your best, Musashi!
배가 고프면 수행할 수 없잖아. 똑바로 해, 무사시!
Got it! I'll do my best-dasu!
알겠소! 힘내겠소!
Hey, are you being cocky to me, the number one of Jipangu-dasu?
어라, 이 녀석, 지팡구 제일의 내게 건방지오!
I'll get you!
이랴!
Thinking to help and yet ending up being helped, for the love no matter the humiliation,
도우려고 하면서도 도와지고, 창피를 당해도 사랑을 위해, 거센 콧김도 타개해 가는 것이 남자의 삶의 태도이다.
Wild flowers are smiling. Go, go, Musashi! Hit hard!
들에 피는 꽃이 웃을 때구나. 가라, 가라, 무사시! 힘껏 부딪혀라!
Sometimes the moon jumps over
허공의 주머니에 달이
the pocket of empty sky
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
Laugh loudly and
큰 소리로 웃으면
morning will come tomorrow
내일에는 아침이 와
Don't worry too much about losing
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Keep going! Go for it!
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
A bare hand is strong
맨손은 강해
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how life is! Look, a chance
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
follows us wagging its tail!
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
Hot springs are the best, as we're tired from all that journey! That's why we stopped by at an inn with a hot spring-dasu,
여행의 노고를 푸는 데에는 온천이 제일! 그래서 무심히 외딴 곳의 온천장 여관에 멈추었지만,
but what?! There's a mountain around here where dead people's spirits gather.
이 무슨! 이 주변엔 죽은 사람의 영혼이 모이는 산이 있다니.
I met again with my beloved Ishimatsu there-dasu! I wish him to go to heaven without getting lost-dasu!
나, 거기서 그리운 이시마츠 씨하고 재회했소! 와, 방황하지 말고 성불하길 바라오!
Next story! Woah! It's Ishimatsu's Ghost-dasu.
다음 이야기! 히익! 이시마츠의 유령이오
It's a stormy great spiritual realm-dasu!
질풍노도의 대영계이오!
Next Episode
다음 이야기
Woah!
히익! 이시마츠의 유령이오
It's Ishimatsu's Ghost!
기대하세요!